## ALESSANDRO BARRETO

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | CIVIL EGINEER

#### **ABOUT**

Technology enthusiast, proactive and constantly seeking new challenges for personal and professional development. Civil Engineer graduated from Santa Catarina Federal University and majoring in Systems Analysis and Development. I have 6 years of experience in the market, working in areas such as modeling, development, data analysis and commercial management. I currently work as a software developer in Europe.

**KNOWLEDGE** 

Computing

Data Analysis

Programming

Automation

Web Development

Comercial Management

• Agile Methodologies

Civil Engineering

Environment

• Client Communication

#### **SKILLS**

#### **TOOLS**

- React
- Next.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- SASS
- Node
- Material UI
- Redux
- Express
- MongoDB
- Docker
- Git
- Microsoft Office

#### **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese

English

Spanish

00000

00000

00000

#### **CONTACT:**

≥ alessandrobarreto1201@gmail.com

(+351) 912-765-320

Lisbon, Portugal

in linkedin.com/in/alessandro--barreto

github.com/AlessandroBarreto

alessandro-barreto.netlify.app/

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Full Stack Developer**

BMW Group | Jan 2022 - Present

• Software development on the BMW e-comerce.

## **Full Stack Developer**

J&A Multi-sector Smart Solutions | May 2021 - Dec 2021

- **Front** Javascript, Typescript; Frameworks/Libs: React, Angular, React Router, Material UI, Axios;
- Back: Javascript, Typescript, Python;
   Frameworks/Libs: Node, Express, Flask, Selenium;
- **Testing**: Jest, React-testing-library;
- **DB**: Mongo;
- **Devops**: Docker, Google Workspace, Bitbucket, Linux, Windows, Git, Postman;
- Scrum.

## **Front End Developer**

Aquarela Advanced Analytics | Jun 2020 - May 2021

- Front: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Figma;
   Frameworks/Libs: React, D3, Material UI, React Router, React Hook
   Form, ContextAPI, Bootstrap, Axios;
- Testing: Jest, Enzyme;
- **DevOps**: Docker, Gitlab, Jenkins, Git, Linux, Postman, VPN, Clickup, Google Workspace;
- Scrum:
- Documentation.

## **Civil Engineer**

Sanova Water Management Solutions | Jun 2018 - Jun 2020

- Commercial management of the Water and Sewage System (SAE) in the city of Pedra Branca/SC/Brazil, focusing on performance indicators, data analysis and python;
- Computational Hydraulic Modeling Projects using Bentley WaterCAD/GEMS and SewerCAD/GEMS softwares;
- Application of Computational Hydraulic Modeling courses for sanitation companies in Brazil using Bentley softwares according to the client's needs;

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Estacio University**

Degree in Systems Analysis and Development | 2020 - 2023

## **Federal University of Santa Catarina**

Degree in Civil Engineering: Sanitation and Environment | 2013 - 2019

## **REFERENCES**

Gilherme Girol

CTO | Sanova Water Management Solutions E-mail: guilherme.girol@sanova.com.br

Lucas Lovato

Software Developer | Clevertech

E-mail: Lucas.lovato@clevertech.biz

Sarah Pfaffenzeller

Software Developer | TheoremOne

E-mail: sarahizabelp@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Full Stack Developer**

BMW Group | Jan 2022 - Present

• I've been working on the ecommerce of vehicles and products of the BMW group, using next, typescript, styled components, express, mongo, aws services and scrum methodology;

#### **Full Stack Developer**

J&A Multi-sector Smart Solutions | May 2021 - Dec 2021

• I worked with front end tools like Angular and wordpress to maintain the websites of J&A Holding companies. I participated in the construction of several robots using Python, pandas, selenium, requests, HTML and CSS for the processes automation and email campaigns of the company Fontes Promotora and creation of screens using React and APIs in Node and express for the consumption of these robots, together with MongoDB. Containerization of applications using Docker, Docker Compose and Linux servers. Construction of the website with the new identity of Fontes Promotora website, using React and covering the desktop and mobile versions;

## **Front End Developer**

Aquarela Advanced Analytics | Jun 2020 - May 2021

At the beginning I worked on the front end (React) together with the back end in the design of an internal platform for queries of
projects, stacks, tools and company workers. Then I worked on the front-end of the Fras-le (automotive segment) company's
artificial intelligence project, focusing on creating screens for data visualization, using React, D3, tests with Jest and Enzyme,
documentation of processes and started experimenting tools like Docker, MongoDB and Python for the back end. Finally, I
worked on the construction of an ontology finder plataform using React;

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

#### **Mentor**

Technovation | Fevereiro de 2021 - Abril de 2021

• Technovation is an international program that encourages children around the world to learn and apply the skills needed to solve real world problems through technology. I acted as a mentor in a team of 4 children between 12 and 14 years old, participating in workshops, meetings and planning to create an environmental awareness app as a final product of the project.